Before they were incorporated, they had to be educated.
Monsters University is a animation, family film directed by Dan Scanlon.
A look at the relationship between Mike and Sulley during their days at Monsters
University — when they weren't necessarily the best of friends.
Mike (voice), played by Billy Crystal.
Sullivan (voice), played by John Goodman.
Randy (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Dean Hardscrabble (voice), played by Helen Mirren.
Squishy (voice), played by Peter Sohn.
Don (voice), played by Joel Murray.
Monsters University is a 2013 American animated coming-of-age comedy film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It is a prequel to Monsters, Inc.
(2001), it was directed by Dan Scanlon (in his feature directorial debut), produced by Kori
Rae, and written by Scanlon and the writing team of Dan Gerson and Robert L.
John Lasseter, Pete Docter, Andrew Stanton and Lee Unkrich
served as the film's executive producers.
The music for the film was composed and conducted by Randy Newman,
making it his seventh collaboration with Pixar.
Monsters University tells the story of the main
characters of Monsters, Inc., James P.
"Sulley" Sullivan and Mike Wazowski, and their experience in
college leading to them becoming best friends.
John Goodman, Billy Crystal, Steve Buscemi, Bob Peterson and
John Ratzenberger reprise their roles as James P.
Sullivan, Mike Wazowski, Randall Boggs, Roz and the Abominable
Snowman, respectively, while Bonnie Hunt, who voiced Ms.
Flint in the original film, voices Mike's childhood teacher Mrs.
New cast members include Helen Mirren, Alfred Molina, Peter Sohn, Joel Murray, Sean
Hayes, Dave Foley, Charlie Day, Nathan Fillion and Aubrey Plaza.
Disney, as the rights holder, had plans for a sequel to Monsters, Inc.
since 2005.
Following disagreements with Pixar, Disney tasked its
Circle 7 Animation unit to make the film.
An early draft of the film was developed; Disney's purchase of Pixar in January
2006 led to the cancellation of Circle 7's version of the film.
A Pixar-made sequel was confirmed in 2010 and in 2011, it was announced that
the film would instead be a prequel titled Monsters University.
Monsters University premiered on June 5, 2013, at the BFI Southbank in London,
England, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 21.
It was accompanied in theaters by a short film, The Blue
Umbrella, directed by Saschka Unseld.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $743 million worldwide against
its $200 million production budget, making it the seventh highest-grossing film of 2013.
An animated short film titled Party Central, which takes place shortly after the events of Monsters
University, premiered in fall 2013 before being released theatrically with Muppets Most Wanted in 2014.
The film explores themes of friendship, monster, door, training camp, dormitory.